Māyā, we are told, she’s ashamed sometimes to come before Kṛṣṇa
据我们所知，玛亚（物质幻象）有时非常羞愧站在奎师那面前
because she has this task of deluding the jīvas.
因为她的任务是迷惑个体灵魂（jīva）
[Maya Works for Krishna]
玛亚是奎师那的手下
But that is our choice— reign in hell [or] serve in heaven.
但那是我们自己的选择：在地狱当头儿，还是在天堂服务
So, for those who opt to reign in hell,
所以对于那些想要在地狱称王称霸的人
which is the deluded position for the eternal servitor of Kṛṣṇa,
他们被迷惑了，忘记了自己是奎师那永恒的仆人
then they need to forget their servitor identity,
当他们忘记了自己仆人的身份
and voyeuristically envision themselves as lords, masters.
自我就开始膨胀，以为自己是大师，是神
So, there is an interesting verse in the 7th chapter of the Bhagavad-gītā:
在《薄伽梵歌》的第七章有一节有意思的诗
daivī hy eṣā guṇa-mayī mama māyā duratyayā
daivī hy eṣā guṇa-mayī mama māyā duratyayā
mām eva ye prapadyante māyām etāṁ taranti te [Bg: 7.14]
mām eva ye prapadyante māyām etāṁ taranti te [Bg: 7.14]
So Kṛṣṇa says, “That Māyā, who’s deluding you,
奎师那说，“玛亚在迷惑你们
who’s, like, impossible to overcome—
你们逃不开她的魔掌
mama māyā— she works for Me.
玛亚，她是我的手下
So, on your own you’ll never be able to overcome her,
因此，靠你们自身的力量将永远无力与她抗衡
to defeat her.”
无法击败她。”
She has some infinite backing.
她有我无量的后盾
Sometimes Prabhupād would say, “We should always remember
有时帕布帕德说，“我们要记住
that we are very small, and Māyā is very great. Don’t …”
我们是如此渺小，但是玛亚很强大，不要..."
He was cautioning us against becoming arrogant
他在提醒我们，在灵性生活中
Saying, “Māyā is great, she is working for Kṛṣṇa,
“玛亚是很伟大的，她在为奎师那工作
this is her service to Kṛṣṇa.”
这是她对奎师那的服务。”
Śiva also complains of his service,
湿婆神（Shiva）也抱怨自己的服务
māyāvādam asac-chāstraṁ pracchannaṁ bauddham ucyate
māyāvādam asac-chāstraṁ pracchannaṁ bauddham ucyate
mayaiva kalpitaṁ devi kalau brāhmaṇa-rūpiṇā [Pp: 25.7]
mayaiva kalpitaṁ devi kalau brāhmaṇa-rūpiṇā [Pp: 25.7]
“In the kali-yuga I take the form of a brāhman,
“在卡利年代，我以一位婆罗门的身份出现
and I preach māyāvād.”
传讲玛亚瓦得（虚无主义）哲学。”
And Guru Mahārāj says in one place, he [Śiva] said to Kṛṣṇa,
Guru Mahārāj有次说，湿婆对奎师那诉苦
“Why do I have to do this? Make people inimical to You
“为什么我要做这样的事？
But it’s to facilitate the free will of the jīvas
但这是为了满足个体灵魂（ jīvas）的自由意愿
and all the spectral range of its expression.
满足灵魂各式各样的自由意志
So, but in this śloka says,
所以，在诗节里说，
daivī hy eṣā guṇa-mayī mama māyā duratyayā.
daivī hy eṣā guṇa-mayī mama māyā duratyayā.
“So, what is the solution?
如何解决呢？
Mām eva ye prapadyante— if you surrender to Me,
Mām eva ye prapadyante—“如果你臣服于我
māyām etāṁ taranti te—
māyām etāṁ taranti te—
then you can cross beyond the influence of Māyā.
便能超越玛亚的束缚
And only that way.
别无他法
I can withdraw her influence over you.”
我可以解除玛亚对你的捆绑。”
karmāṇi nirdahati kintu ca bhakti-bhājām [Bs: 5.54]
karmāṇi nirdahati kintu ca bhakti-bhājām [Bs: 5.54]
It’s all in the Brahma-saṁhitā.
这些都记录在Brahma-saṁhitā
When someone comes in connection with Guru–Gaurāṅga, Rādhā–Govinda,
那些与古茹、 主高冉嘎、茹阿达–哥文达建立联结的人
they are no longer under the normal laws of karma,
他们已经开始超越业报法则的牵引
they come under a different jurisdiction
来到了不同的评判准则中
because they’re leaving the out-carrying current
因为，他们正脱离目前的逆流
that’s going away from the central conception of the Absolute
那股远离绝对真理中心的逆流
and entering the in-carrying current,
而进入服务
which is going towards the central conception of the Absolute,
将自己置身于服务的洪流
in the service.
奔向绝对真理的中心
So, but Māyā is there to draw contrast
但是玛亚在那儿提供对比参照
between the mundane and the spiritual,
划清物质和灵性之间的区别
the formal and the substantial,
形式和实质之间
fictitious and real devotion— many things.
虚伪和真实的奉爱之间等等
So it’s necessary, just like in a class,
所以那是必要的
and sees if the students can detect it.
看看学生们能不能分辨
That’s also a type of learning.
那也是一种学习
But Māyā’s serving indirectly because in that sense
因此，玛亚在间接服务奎师那
for want of the sufferings of material existence
因为那些想继续在物质世界受苦的人
there is a lack of impetus to take spiritual life seriously.
是因为缺少认真追求灵性生命的动力
It’s in the 7th chapter of Bhagavad-gītā:
《薄伽梵歌》第七章：
catur-vidhā bhajante māṁ janāḥ su-kṛtino ’rjuna [Bg: 7.16]
catur-vidhā bhajante māṁ janāḥ su-kṛtino ’rjuna [Bg: 7.16]
when Kṛṣṇa says, “There are four types of people
奎师那说，
the distressed—those in economic distress;
穷困潦倒的人
those who are just stressed;
心力交瘁的人
the jijñāsā—inquisitive;
jijñāsā—被好奇心驱使的人
the jñāni—the people who’re really trying to mind spiritual knowledge.”
jñāni—那些真正渴望灵性真知的人
They’ll be inclined towards this.
这些人会走上这条路
But so there needs to be some impetus.
所以他们需要一些原动力
So, in that way Māyā is serving Kṛṣṇa
所以，玛亚在用这种方式为奎师那服务
and serving us by giving us impetus
也在服务我们
take shelter of sādhu, śāstra, guru, Vaiṣṇav.
寻求圣人、圣典、古茹、外士纳瓦（sādhu, sāstra, guru, Vaiṣṇav）的庇护
Hare Kṛṣṇa.
哈瑞 奎师那